"I was so happy
“我很開心
I could be kind to you.
能夠溫柔對待老師
I never imagined it would turn out like this."
但我從沒想到事情會變成這樣”
You're lying.
妳在說謊
Lying to yourself.
自欺欺人
I know that.
我知道
But before I even realized,
等我發覺時
my eyes would follow him.
我的目光也離不開他了
I…
我…
I've fallen in love with you.
我喜歡上老師了
Please don't come to hate me.
請不要討厭我
I'm being crazy.
我瘋了嗎？
Something's wrong with me.
我太不對勁了
He's a student.
他是學生哦
It'll ruin your life.
會毀了妳的
I know that.
我知道
Nothing more will happen.
不會再有什麼事了
I promise.
絕對不會
Your teaching career is just beginning.
妳的教師生涯才正要開始
Don't look at me like that.
別這樣看著我
Remember what you said before?
妳之前不是說過嗎？
You fell for your husband after your trip to Okinawa.
妳跟老公去沖繩時 對一個男人心動了
At the hotel pool!
在飯店的泳池！
That wiry and ripped plain-faced guy.
那個表情冷冷的精瘦猛男
Totally my type.
確實是我的菜
He blew up my swimming ring with ease.
他很輕鬆地幫我把泳圈充好氣
It made my heart beat.
害我心動了一下
Yes, that's all it is.
沒錯，就是那種程度而已
-That's all. -But that's all thanks to Shotaro.
-僅此而已 -不過這都是多虧了勝太郎哦
When you get engaged you see your life plan ahead of you,
決定要結婚，開始有人生計畫之後
and everything around you suddenly feels safe.
周遭的環境會突然變成舒適圈
That's why you start seeking out something dangerous.
所以會被外面的危險事物吸引
Listen, Hijiri.
聽著，聖
You need to be grateful towards Shotaro for your happiness.
妳要感謝勝太郎帶給妳的幸福
You're right.
妳說的對
I totally agree with you.
我也是這麼想
Good morning.
早安
-Good morning.
-早安
Is it just me, or is Hijiri in a really good mood today?
是我的錯覺嗎？ 今天小聖好像心情很好
Maybe.
好像是
Good morning.
同學們早安
Today, I'll be announcing the long-awaited results for your finals.
今天我會公佈 大家期待已久的期末成績
We haven't been waiting at all!
我們完全沒有期待！
Quiet down!
大家安靜！
Okay, Iwasaki.
好，我要發下去囉，岩崎同學
Yes.
是
Akira is being preyed on.
阿晶被盯上了
What?
什麼？
I don't know if she's a predator or getting cold feet,
我不知道她到底是淫蕩教師 還是不想結婚
but everyone says she's weird.
但大家都在說她很奇怪
I'm worried for Kuroiwa!
我很擔心黑岩！
What about Ms. Suenaga?
老師怎麼了？
Great job in home economics.
家政科考得很不錯
Thank you.
謝謝
Ebihara.
海老原同學
What's wrong, Runachi?
怎麼了，瑠奈？
Just a bit of self-loathing.
只是有點討厭自己
Kuroiwa.
黑岩同學
Great job, but your English needs a little work.
考得很好，英文要再加把勁
Okay.
好的
Kosaka.
香阪同學
What the hell is this?
這是什麼？
I promise--
我覺得很好玩，但我答應…
-Screw you! -Stop, Kuroiwa!
-開什麼玩笑！ -住手，黑岩！
What are you doing? Stop!
你們在幹嘛？住手！
Stop that.
不要這樣
Hold on, come on.
等下，不要
Give it back.
還我
Not bad, man.
不錯嘛
-Sit down. -Let me get in on this.
-回座位坐下 -我也要加入
Sit down!
回座位坐下！
One sec.
等一下
With the term ending, summer vacation is around the corner.
期末結束，暑假就快來了
-And summer vacation means… -Ding!
-說到暑假的話… -叮咚！
The Fireworks Festival!
子星平煙火大會！
Thank you!
謝謝！
Yes, there's that, too.
對，確實也有煙火大會
But we have the summer course.
不過在這之前，我們還有暑期輔導
-It's a five day course. -You're not listed as teaching.
-為期五天 -沒有老師的課
Are you going on summer vacation?
老師要放暑假嗎？
That's so unfair!
真不公平
Don't be like that.
別這樣嘛
I'll be here to chaperon the festival, so see you there.
煙火大會我會負責到場監督 大家在會場上見吧
Okay!
好！
I guess that means we'll barely see Hijiri this summer.
這麼說暑假幾乎不會見到小聖了
Where are we going, anyway?
話說我們到底要去哪？
Summer?
夏天？
What? That's so stupid.
什麼？好蠢啊
It's so hot, it's melting so fast.
真熱，都融化了
-Hey. -Huh?
-喂 -咦？
-I won. -What?
-我中了 -什麼？
You won a twofer!
中了兩支啊！
Give it!
給我！
-Idiot! -Trade with me!
-笨蛋！ -跟我換！
You idiot!
你這個笨蛋！
Don't try to steal my first kiss!
別想奪走我的初吻！
You'll pay for that.
會讓你好看的
It's still here.
還在這
Where you going? A bike?
要去哪啊？腳踏車？
What's it doing here?
怎麼在這裡？
Kuroiwa, did you fall?
黑岩同學，你摔下來了嗎？
Did you hit your head?
你有撞到頭嗎？
Are you serious about Hijiri?
你對小聖是認真的嗎？
Like for real serious?
超級無敵認真嗎？
You're ambitious, I'll give you that.
真服了你有這勇氣
You know what your chances are of it being reciprocated?
你知道你們兩情相悅的可能性嗎？
Zero! Nothing!
是零！沒有！
You think so?
是嗎？
Hmm?
嗯？
I'll be here to chaperone the festival, so see you there.
煙火大會我會負責到場監督 大家在會場上見吧
What, you want to go to this?
怎麼了？你要去嗎？
Hey!
喂！
Don't leave me! Wait! Kuroiwa!
不要丟下我啦！等一下，黑岩！
Hey you, that's dangerous!
喂，很危險！
Sorry!
對不起！
Okay, this is good.
沒問題，很好
As long as I don't see him during summer vacation. I'm sure…
只要這個夏天 不要和他見面，我肯定…
Ms. Suenaga.
老師
Ms. Kuroiwa.
黑岩太太
Hello.
妳好
You're feeling better now?
妳身體恢復了嗎？
I need to speak with you.
我有話跟妳說
About Akira.
是關於阿晶的事
Fireworks!
煙火！
Ms. Suenaga, after the fireworks…
老師，煙火大會結束之後 妳可以跟我…
I want you, Kawai.
我想要你，川合
Saying you were watching Akira, I was just a little worried.
說妳在課堂上都在看阿晶 我難免會有些擔心
I like you the way you are!
我就喜歡這樣的妳！
Iwasaki said that?
岩崎同學說的嗎？
Of course I didn't take her seriously.
當然，我並沒有當真
But she said
但她說
you would watch Akira during class.
妳在課堂上都在看阿晶
During the study camp, instead of just dropping him off at the station,
讀書合宿時 明明只要送他去車站就好
you stayed with him until the last train stop.
卻特地送他到終點站
After hearing her say all that, I got a little worried.
聽到這些話，我難免會有些擔心
For Runa.
擔心瑠奈
What?
什麼？
I'm sorry to trouble you with this, Ms. Suenaga.
很抱歉打擾妳，老師
It seems that things didn't work out between her and Akira.
瑠奈她似乎跟阿晶相處不順利
There's a chance she resents you for it.
她可能因此怨恨妳
Oh, I'm not sure about that.
哦，應該不是吧
Anyway, she's not acting normal, so please keep an eye out for her.
總之她不太對勁，請妳多多注意她
Of course, I understand.
當然，我知道了
Look at the time.
已經這麼晚啦
I should get back to work.
我要回去工作了
KOBOSHIDAIRA FIREWORKS FESTIVAL
（子星平煙火大會）
That's amazing! Wow!
好漂亮！哇！
AKIRA KUROIWA
（學生姓名：黑岩晶）
Ms. Suenaga!
老師！
Thank you!
謝謝！
THESE ARE VERY GOOD GRADES.
（成績非常出色）
TRY TO FOCUS ON YOUR LIBERAL ARTS STUDIES.
（文科方面需要多加強）
The person you are calling is not able to answer the phone at this time.
您現在撥打的電話暫時無法接通
Kawai.
川合
Hand in your latest proposal.
把最新版的 生產效率改善計畫書交上來
Yes, ma'am.
好
-Konishi, the operator manual? -Coming up!
-小西，操作手冊呢？ -就快好了！
-This isn't a soba restaurant. -Sorry.
-這裡不是蕎麥麵店 -對不起
Um.
嗯
I…
我…
I appreciate the sentiment, but…
謝謝妳的這份心意，但…
-I have Hijiri. -I think it's time to go.
-我已經有聖了 -該回去了
-Huh? -Good night.
-咦？ -辛苦了
U-Um…
嗯…
-What? -Nothing.
-怎麼了？ -沒事
Oh, right.
哦，對了
You're going to have to go on the Singapore trip for me.
麻煩你代替我去新加坡出差
Singapore?
新加坡？
With Ms. Haraguchi.
跟原口小姐一起
What?
咦？
We're at the crucial early stage.
我們正處於關鍵的早期階段
The hotel will be the Seawood. For dinner Bak Kut Teh.
飯店訂西伍德，晚餐就選肉骨茶
Can you arrange it?
可以安排嗎？
Affirmative.
好的
-Here you go. -Thanks.
-給妳 -謝謝
I was able to take time off this summer.
暑假我有休假
Can I come visit you?
我可以去找你嗎？
When?
什麼時候？
July 20th to the 24th.
7月20到24日
Sorry, they just told me I had to go to Singapore.
不行，剛剛他們 通知我要去新加坡出差
Really?
真的嗎？
That's too bad then.
那就沒辦法了
SUMMER VACATION
（暑假）
Hold up, you guys.
你們等一下啦
Now you've done it.
這下搞砸了
-Hold up, Shiraishi. -Oh, boy.
-白石，等一下 -糟糕
I can't show this to my mom.
這個不能給我媽看到
Wanna hang out somewhere?
怎麼辦？要去哪裡玩嗎？
Shake!
搖！
Nice, let's go!
好啊，走吧！
-Score! -Hey!
-拿到了！ -喂！
-You got two fives! -Give it back!
-有兩個五分耶！ -還我！
Show me!
給我看！
SWIMMING COMPETITION ENTRY FORM
（游泳比賽報名表）
It's never ending.
不管怎麼做也做不完
How do we have more work during vacation?
怎麼進入暑假，工作反而增加了？
Three courses in July and a practice game in between.
七月有三場研修，還有練習比賽
-Plus there's "that." -"That"?
-除此之外還有“那個” -“那個”？
-The fireworks. -Oh, it's your first time, isn't it?
-煙火大會 -末永老師是第一次參加吧？
Yes, I'm looking forward to it!
是呀，我很期待！
I hear its known for its underwater fireworks!
聽說這個水中煙火很有名！
So naive!
太天真了！
You won't get to see them.
根本沒時間看煙火！
We have to patrol.
我們要一直巡邏
The students love to wander and get in fights with rival schools.
學生都在到處閒逛 還會跟別校的學生打架
Really?
真的嗎？
-Ms. Suenaga. -Yes!
-末永老師 -是！
Congratulations on surviving your first term.
恭喜妳撐過第一個學期
I wasn't sure you were going to make it at first,
一開始真不知道妳會做得怎麼樣
but you managed to get through it.
但總算是熬過來了
-Thank you so much for all of your help. -It's nothing.
-感謝大家幫忙 -哪裡
It's always tough when you first get to a new school.
剛到新學校都會遇到很多困難
The very first junior high I was assigned, it was such a rough school!
我被分派的第一所國中 真是一所逞凶鬥狠的學校！
-They had bamboo swords! -Swords?
-還會帶竹刀來！ -竹刀？
Yes, swords! And the principal--
是的，竹刀！校長還…
This is a long story, so I should tell it over drinks.
這個故事說來話長，我們邊喝邊聊
Ms. Suenaga, this is missing a parent's signature.
末永老師，這份沒有家長簽名哦
-Huh? -You'll need to get it signed right away.
-什麼？ -這個得趕快簽署才行
-Isn't that right, Ms. Shioya? -Right?
-對吧，鹽谷老師？ -對吧？
Yes, please do.
是啊，拜託妳了
And this is missing the course.
還有這張，沒有填寫課程
-I'm sorry. -Check it over.
-對不起 -檢查一下
AKIRA KUROIWA
（3年1班6號，姓名：黑岩晶）
-Oh, Ms. Suenaga. -Hello.
-哎呀，老師 -妳好
Akira didn't mention it at all. I'll sign it right away.
阿晶什麼都沒說，抱歉，我馬上簽
Would you like some tea?
要不要喝杯茶？
That's okay, I won't be staying.
沒關係，我馬上就離開
Ms. Suenaga?
老師？
Why are you here?
妳怎麼在這裡？
She came to get this signed.
她來讓我簽這個
I'm sorry.
對不起
-Here. -Thank you.
-這裡 -謝謝
-I should be going. -My future!
-那我告辭了 -我的生涯諮詢
Can we discuss it?
可以談談嗎？
Just for a second?
就一下？
The local high school?
你要去附近的高中嗎？
That's all I've really come up with.
我現在只能想到這個
Come on, why don't you have a more serious discussion?
真是的，你更認真點跟老師討論吧
You made her stay after all.
畢竟還特地留老師下來
What do you want to be?
你想成為什麼樣的大人？
-What… -How about this.
-什麼… -這樣吧
Instead of the coming three years.
先別想未來這三年
Imagine the person you want to become, and think of the steps you have to take.
你先想像自己想成為什麼樣的人 然後想想要怎麼做
Can you picture the school?
腦中有浮現想去的學校了嗎？
Think about it over the summer.
你要趁暑假期間慢慢思考
KANAGAWA HIGH SCHOOL ENTRANCE EXAM GUIDE
（《神奈川縣高中入學考試指南》）
You've reached the Kuroiwas.
你好，這裡是黑岩家
-I'll be right back. -Okay.
-我馬上回來 -好的
Thank you for calling.
謝謝你打過來
Yes.
是
Is that so?
是嗎？
I will check things on my end.
我這邊確認一下
Well.
那麼
I should be going.
我該走了
-Ms. Suenaga. -What?
-老師 -什麼？
Yes, I understand.
是的，我知道了
After the fireworks, would you…
煙火大會結束之後，妳可以跟我…
I'll call back later.
我再回電給您
Goodbye.
再見
Ms. Suenaga.
老師
Are you leaving?
妳要走了嗎？
Yes, excuse me.
是的，我先告辭了
I'm sorry for the trouble.
麻煩妳了
Thank you.
謝謝
Goodbye.
再見
-Take care. -Thank you.
-路上小心 -謝謝
Alright! All done.
好了！都做完了
My five days of summer vacation have started.
我的五天暑假開始了
How is work coming along?
你工作還順利嗎？
Let's go.
走吧
Okay.
好
I'll start getting things ready.
我該開始準備了
So we can get married next year.
為了明年能順利舉行婚禮
Thanks!
謝謝！
You're the best.
麻煩妳了！
WEDDING PLANNING 101
（婚禮準備完全解析指南）
HOW MUCH TO SPEND ON THE HONEYMOON
（蜜月旅行的花費）
All of these sentences use "to" plus the root verb.
這些句子中“以”要加動詞原型
Take this sentence for example.
拿這個句子為例
"Buy" becomes an infinitive.
“買”變成不定詞
This means purchasing the book was…
這個意思是為了去買書…
Kuroiwa!
黑岩！
You want Suenaga's phone number?
你要末永的手機號碼嗎？
Only the parents know this one.
只有家長才知道這號碼
I got it easy because my mom's password is my birthday.
我媽手機的密碼是她生日 所以輕鬆就拿到手了
Want to go to the fireworks together?
要不要一起去煙火大會？
You can have the number if you do.
如果你願意跟我去，我就給你
So? I'll be wearing a yukata.
怎麼樣？我會穿浴衣哦
I don't appreciate this.
我不想這樣
So stop.
別再這樣子了
I wasn't joking when I said it.
我說那句話不是在捉弄妳
I love you.
我喜歡老師
I want to see you the day of the fireworks.
煙火大會那天，我想見妳
I'll be waiting at the Amanosaki Shrine after the fireworks.
煙火結束後，我在天野崎神社等妳
Let's go strategize for the meeting over drinks.
我們去喝一杯，然後討論明天的會議
What's with that dazed pigeon look?
怎麼了？一臉目瞪口呆的表情
I'm not sure.
我搞不太懂
What do you think?
妳在想什麼？
Um.
那個…
Um, what?
那個什麼？
You know.
妳懂的
Isn't this awkward?
好像有點尷尬？
Never mind.
沒關係
Let's drop it.
別提這件事了
Let's talk about tomorrow.
來討論明天的事吧
The night I kissed you.
那天晚上吻了你後
I'd been thinking.
我想過了
Something felt strange.
感覺很奇怪
Like in my gut.
打從心底地
Or maybe not.
又好像不是
But also something exciting.
可是心情很興奮
Seems really vague.
非常微妙呢
Which is why I wanted to know.
所以我也想知道
What this feeling was.
這份心情到底是怎麼回事
Did I fall for you?
我喜歡上你了嗎？
Or not.
還是沒有
But
但是
I have Hijiri.
我有聖
Your rocky relationship.
那不太順利的感情
We're doing fine, probably.
很順利啦，大概
There's probably someone else in the picture.
大概有其他男人
No, there's not.
沒有
Probably.
大概
Did you ask her?
你問過她嗎？
Straight up.
直接地
What?
什麼？
You need to ask her directly.
一定要乾脆地直接問她
"Things have been off."
“最近妳感覺很奇怪”
-"Is something going on?" -Ms. Haraguchi.
-“是不是發生了什麼事？” -原口小姐
"If you don't tell me the truth, then you'd better get to Osaka…"
“聽著，妳如果不從實招來 那妳現在馬上就來大阪…”
Your own room, please.
請回妳的房間吧
Let me know what happens.
問清楚之後告訴我結果
Knock once for no issue, or if there is…
沒有問題就敲一聲，如果有問題…
Knock twice on our wall here.
就敲牆壁兩次
Good night.
晚安
So bland.
太淡了
What a fail.
失敗了
MEAT AND POTATO STEW
（馬鈴薯燉肉）
I'LL BE WAITING AT THE AMANOSAKI SHRINE AFTER THE FIREWORKS.
（煙火結束後 我在天野崎神社等妳）
DELETE
（刪除）
CAN YOU TALK?
（方便說話嗎？）
Sorry I couldn't be with you over summer break, Hijiri.
對不起，聖，不能陪妳過暑假
Your trip must be tough.
出差很辛苦吧
I just got back to the hotel.
現在剛回到飯店
Take a load off.
辛苦你了
That's right.
對了
I'll be in Tokyo next Saturday, so I'll try to swing by.
下週六我會回東京，也許能去找妳
-That's the fireworks. -Fireworks?
-那天有煙火 -煙火？
There's a big festival here.
我這裡有煙火大會
You going?
妳要去嗎？
With who?
和誰？
I'll be on patrol with the other teachers.
我會和學校的其他老師去巡邏
I see, for work.
是嗎？是工作啊
-So… -Oh!
-那個… -對了！
I found a few interesting venues.
我找到了幾個很有趣的結婚會場
Look, it has a pool.
你看，這個有泳池
You can add balloons for 70,000 yen.
在泳池上放氣球的話要加七萬
So expensive!
好貴！
This one is like a camping style.
這個是露營風
You can cut the cake while barbecuing.
聽說可以一邊烤肉一邊切蛋糕
-Huh… -There's so many options.
-嗯… -有這麼多選擇
-I'll send the links later. -Okay.
-等一下把資料傳給你 -好
KOBOSHIDAIRA FIREWORKS FESTIVAL
（子星平煙火大會）
You got asked out?
他邀妳出去？
To meet today?
今天見面啊？
The yukata suits you.
這件浴衣好適合妳
-So pretty. -Yeah?
-真漂亮 -是嗎？
Who cares, forget about me for now!
別管這個，別說我的事了！
Don't tell me you're going to take up that boy's invitation
別跟我說妳會傻傻答應那男孩的邀請
and go to the meeting place.
跑去約好的地方見他
I didn't reply.
我沒有回他
I already blocked the number.
我已經封鎖他了
I see.
是嗎？
It's all over now.
已經結束了
That's good then.
那就好
Anyway, what is Shotaro up to during such an important time!
話說回來，這麼重要的時候 勝太郎到底在做什麼啊？
He seems busy.
他好像很忙
He does text me regularly though.
不過他很常傳訊息給我
You're not doing this wedding alone, you two need to share the planning.
可是婚禮不是一個人舉行 必須要兩個人一起商量討論
-Or you'll lose the heat. -Heat?
-否則熱度會減退哦 -熱度？
Just like tea, if you leave it, your feelings begin to cool.
就跟茶一樣 如果放著不管，激情就會冷卻
Which is why you need to be together, and keep things nice and hot.
所以要陪在彼此身邊 拼命地維持愛情的溫度
Old construction machinery are simpler compared to newer models,
由於舊款工程機械 跟新型相較構造簡單
making them easier to repair on site.
在當地需要維修時會比較容易
To establish this set of businesses,
為了確立這一系列的業務
we should conduct research on emerging markets…
要在各個新興市場進行研究…
HIJIRI
（小聖）
Akira, lunch is ready.
阿晶，午餐好了
Later.
等一下吃
Act like you can live without that person.
要好像自己的世界 就算少了她也無所謂
Love works out better when you think that way.
這樣想戀愛會比較順利
Strangely enough.
很神奇哦
Well, not like things ever actually work out
不過實際上就是無法控制
which is why I'm still single.
所以我才會到現在還單身
Not seeing Ms. Hijiri over summer break might be good for you.
暑假暫時別跟聖老師見面 也許會比較好
When you fall for a teacher, you don't have a chance.
老實說對方是老師 你們也沒什麼可能
Why?
為什麼？
Why does everyone say that?
為什麼大家都要這麼說？
Why can't I fall for Ms. Suenaga?
為什麼我不能喜歡老師？
Well, because that's the rule.
因為這是規則
Well, I don't care about your grown-up rules.
我才不在乎這種大人的規則
But Ms. Hijiri has to live following those grown-up rules.
但是聖老師就是活在 這種大人規則的世界裡
Eating is a rule.
吃飯也是規則
I microwaved it.
我已經微波好了哦
Checking social media for any trace of cheating?
檢查社群網站 看有沒有劈腿的蛛絲馬跡？
You scared me.
妳嚇到我了
-Kawai. -Yes?
-川合 -是？
That's the beginning of the end.
你一旦這麼做就結束了
It's unbearable to watch.
我實在是看不下去
Stop the act, please.
別演了啦，拜託
These business trips are exhausting.
出差真是累人啊
You think we'll get off early?
今天可以早一點回去嗎？
I need to stop by somewhere, so I'm only going with you part way.
我要去一個地方，會在中途下車
Where are you going?
妳要去哪裡？
KOBOSHIDAIRA FIREWORKS
（子星平煙火大會）
That's Hijiri's?
這是在聖那邊？
Do you want to come with me?
要一起去嗎？
Okay, Ms. Suenaga, your flashlight and ID.
末永老師，妳的手電筒和識別證
-Watch your step around here. -Okay.
-會場不好走，要小心點 -好的
-You'll be in charge of the east side.
-東邊就拜託你們了 -好
-Let's go then. -Let's go.
-走吧
Looks like everyone is having fun.
大家看起來好開心
It's nice.
真好啊
You'd usually come with a boyfriend.
妳本來應該和男友一起來吧
Yakisoba, takoyaki, or something else?
要吃炒麵，章魚燒，還是別的？
Kuroiwa and Iwasaki?
黑岩跟岩崎？
When did that happen?
什麼時候發生的？
Yakisoba?
炒麵？
You ready to eat?
要去吃嗎？
-I'm not hungry. -You're not?
-我不餓 -不餓嗎？
I'm glad they're having fun.
真好，看起來很開心
Let's head that way.
我們去那裡吧
Hey.
喂
I told you ahead of time. Why didn't you dress up like me?
我一早和你說了 你為什麼不和我一樣穿浴衣？
I don't own a yukata.
我就沒有浴衣啊
It's Sis's boyfriend!
是姐姐的男友！
So handsome!
好帥！
Hey, come on!
喂，別鬧了！
Go back to Mom.
快回媽媽那裡去
Have fun!
要玩得開心哦！
How big was your family again?
妳家有幾個人？
It's my mom and five siblings.
我媽和五個兄弟姐妹
My dad got sick and died.
我爸因為生病去世了
Are you like really remarkable?
難道說妳其實很了不起？
What?
你在說什麼啊？
Let's go.
走吧
It's not ripped yet.
還沒破
One more please.
再來一個
Here you go.
來
I have four, no five.
四個，不對，是五個
Come on.
快點
-Wait… -You suck at it.
-等… -你好遜
I got one!
撈到一個了！
YAKITORI
（炒麵）
It's been a while since my last festival.
好久沒參加祭典了
You think you can tell me now?
妳也該告訴我了吧？
Why did you come here?
妳要來這裡做什麼？
Isn't it obvious?
不是明擺著嗎？
I came for…
我當然是來…
Oh!
哦！
-Hijiri. -Candy apples.
-聖 -蘋果糖
What?
什麼？
You're not going?
你不過去嗎？
I don't want to disturb her working.
她在工作，我晚點聯繫她
I see.
是嗎？
Could you find us a seat then?
那可以幫我們找個位置坐嗎？
-I'm going to buy a candy apple. -Okay.
-我去買蘋果糖 -好的
CANDY APPLES
（蘋果糖）
It's beautiful.
好漂亮
Summer!
夏天！
It's so pretty.
真的很美
Wow!
好厲害！
Kuroiwa, let's go over there.
黑岩，去那邊吧
Hurry!
快點！
Hey, watch it you guys. Be careful.
喂，你們小心點
Can you check over that way?
那邊麻煩妳去巡邏
-I'll go this way. -Okay.
-我走這邊 -好的
Meet up later.
等下見
What's this?
這是什麼？
Is that shaved ice? Careful not to eat too much.
那是刨冰嗎？別吃太多哦
Okay, sorry.
是，對不起
-Joffe. -Yes?
-喬飛 -是
You don't need to go see the fireworks?
你不用去煙火大會嗎？
I have sensitive eardrums.
我的耳膜本來就很脆弱
Thank you.
謝謝
So I don't like fireworks.
所以不喜歡煙火
Which is why I'm in an environmentally friendly Hawaiian band.
所以我才加入 對環境友善的夏威夷樂團
Ta-da!
妳看！
-What about you, Boss? -Hmm?
-社長呢？ -嗯？
How about it?
怎麼了？
You used to go out all the time.
妳以前經常去吧
Lucky you.
真好啊
That's ancient history.
陳年往事了
You know,
我感覺
I feel so good right now.
現在非常開心
You said before,
妳之前說過吧
that you're prepared.
妳做好準備了
But at the very least,
但是至少
unlike Suenaga, I came here prepared to get a little hurt.
我跟末永不一樣 我來之前已經做好多少會傷心的覺悟
You're strong and remarkable.
妳很了不起又堅強
And I've just…
而我只是…
I'm sorry if I hurt you.
如果我傷害了妳，對不起
I told Ms. Suenaga
我跟老師
that I loved her.
告白了
What?
什麼？
But she didn't take me seriously at all.
可是她完全不當一回事
And everyone keeps warning me.
大家也一直告誡我
TAKOYAKI
（章魚燒）
I just…
我只是…
want to have fun with her,
想和她開心地在一起
and be nice to her.
溫柔地對她好
That's all.
這樣而已
I just want
我只想
to punch you.
揍你
What?
咦？
You tick me off so much!
你讓我很不爽！
Excuse me.
不好意思
Ms. Haraguchi!
原口小姐！
Why are you here?
妳怎麼在這裡？
And you, Hijiri?
妳呢，小聖？
Why are you so rattled?
妳怎麼這麼慌張？
Oh, I'm not.
哦，我沒有呀
Kawai's here too.
川合也來了
With me.
和我一起來的
What?
什麼？
Do you love Kawai?
妳喜歡川合嗎？
Why would--
為什麼要…
Answer me, Hijiri.
回答我，小聖
Do you love Kawai?
妳喜歡川合嗎？
Yes.
是的
More than anyone else?
比其他任何人都喜歡嗎？
He's number one?
他排第一位嗎？
I'm sorry, I'm not sure what this is about.
對不起，我不懂妳要問什麼
Of course I love him.
我當然喜歡他
We're engaged.
我們已經訂婚了
We're getting married.
都準備結婚了
Why?
為什麼？
You don't have to.
有什麼關係呢？
If there's someone else, what's wrong with that?
如果妳喜歡別人，那又怎麼樣？
You know,
話說回來
now I'm interested.
我反而對妳有興趣了
To see plain old Hijiri hold such passion.
乍看之下很平凡的妳 居然藏著這麼炙熱的內心
It's interesting, and it'd be a disservice for you not to enjoy it.
很有意思，若不好好享受就太可惜了
Pretending to be normal, worried about society.
假裝平凡，擔心世俗的眼光
Hiding your true self.
隱藏真實的自己
Now, that's lame.
那樣才是最遜的作法
Have a proper talk with Kawai.
好好跟川合談
Or else nobody can
否則無論是誰
progress any further.
都無法繼續前進的
And that's a problem for me.
這樣我很困擾
What do you mean by that?
妳這話是什麼意思？
Ms. Suenaga.
末永老師
Long time!
好久不見！
How've you been?
妳還好嗎？
I should get back to work.
我該回去工作了
-Keep up the good work. -You too.
-辛苦了
ENTER PINCODE
（輸入密碼）
HIJIRI
（小聖）
I WANT TO SEE YOU THE DAY OF THE FIREWORKS.
（煙火大會那天，我想見妳）
Attention all attendees,
大家請注意
the Koboshidaira Fireworks Festival has concluded.
子星平煙火大會到此已圓滿結束
Please ensure you have all of your belongings as you make your way home.
回程時請別忘記隨身物品…
I can't.
不行了
I give up.
我放棄
You can have the rest.
來，剩下的給你
No answer.
她沒接
Maybe she's still working.
是不是還在工作啊？
I want more.
我很想要
Of what?
什麼？
Of you.
我想要你，川合
So…
所以…
if you guys are having trouble,
如果你們之間有問題
and it looks like you're heading into an unhappy marriage, I'll stop it.
如果你看起來將步入 不幸的婚姻，我會阻止你
So tell me.
所以告訴我
If it's one knock or two.
是敲一聲，還是兩聲？
Good job tonight.
今晚辛苦了
So strange.
真奇怪
I can't believe nothing happened.
居然沒發生什麼事
This year was nice and mellow.
今年真是平安順利啊
Lots of students came with family this year.
今年很多學生是跟家人來吧
Oh it's Sis!
哦，是姐姐！
Nice, right?
很好玩，對吧？
Did you have fun?
好玩嗎？
Okay, folks.
好的，各位
This year was miraculously uneventful.
今年奇蹟般地順利結束了
Good work, everyone.
辛苦大家了
We'll be entering summer break now.
接下來將進入暑假
But kids these days are harder to read.
現在的孩子不像以前那麼好懂
There will always be signs if someone is troubled.
如果有問題一定會有徵兆
Please keep a careful eye out for your students.
大家一定要仔細留意各自的學生
Thank you.
要再麻煩大家了
Excuse me, I have to get off.
對不起，我要下車
You know, I think she said her boyfriend's here.
這麼說，她好像說男友有來
Or maybe not.
還是好像沒有
Which is it?
是有還是沒有？
SHOTARO
（勝太郎）
Ah! No!
哎！等一下！
Ms. Suenaga.
老師
What are you doing?
妳在做什麼？
It's dangerous.
這樣很危險
Also, people will think you're crazy.
這樣別人會以為妳在做傻事
Hot!
很燙！
Oh, crap!
哎，糟糕！
It's over already?
已經結束了嗎？
What about you?
你呢？
Why?
為什麼？
Because you never showed up.
我在等妳，但妳沒來
Here.
這個給妳
Please wear it.
給妳穿吧
There's a lot of glass around here.
附近有很多玻璃碎片
But then you'll cut your foot.
可是這樣會割傷你的腳
I wanted to see you
我今天想見妳
to ask you something.
是因為我想問妳
How do you feel about me?
老師妳是怎麼看我的？
I wanted to hear it directly from you.
我想聽妳親口說
So, how do you feel?
妳對我是什麼想法？
I…
我…
I'm getting married.
我要結婚了
I know.
我知道
He's a really great guy.
他是個很好的男人
Smart, and positive.
很聰明，也總是非常積極
When I'm with him,
跟他在一起
I feel like I'm getting pulled up.
總覺得一直被他帶領著向前走
Not as the failure I am, but to make me a better, more positive--
不是這樣糟糕的我 而應該是更完美、更積極的…
I like you as you are now!
我喜歡原本的妳！
I like you the way you are!
我就喜歡這樣的妳！
Even if it
就算是
has to be an affair.
婚外情我也沒關係
I can't do that.
我做不到
Then.
那麼
Be with me,
只有今天就好
just for today.
請跟我在一起
Then I'll…
然後，我…
give up on you.
就會放棄妳
And what would we do?
我們在一起要做什麼？
I…
我…
I want to be kind to you.
想溫柔地對妳好
You being my teacher, me being your student,
不管是老師學生的身份
you having a fiancé…
還是妳有未婚夫的事
Just forget all that.
全部都忘掉
I want to get to know you.
我只想瞭解老師
I want you to learn--
我也想要妳瞭解我…
So once you get to know me, you'll be able to forget me?
一旦瞭解了，你就能忘了我嗎？
Yes.
是的
Even if learning more,
即使瞭解過後
could make you fall harder for me.
會令你更喜歡我
But if I don't forget--
可是我不忘記的話…
Sorry, never mind.
對不起，沒事了
If I don't, I'll get you in trouble, as my teacher!
不忘記的話，老師會很困擾吧！
Don't call me that.
別叫我老師
I don't deserve to be.
我不配
I don't deserve to be called a teacher.
我沒資格被叫老師
What is this?
怎麼回事？
Making me embarrass myself.
在她面前出醜
Not giving me an answer.
卻得不到回應
It's all
開始覺得
becoming a pain.
很難受
What is it
老師想
that you want to do?
怎麼做？
I want to go home.
我想回家
Honestly, me too.
老實說，我也是
May I do it again?
可以再一次嗎？
Calm down.
冷靜點
I don't care what anyone says.
我不在意別人怎麼說
I…
我…
I love you.
我喜歡老師
I was happy.
我很開心
So happy that I could be kind to you.
能溫柔對待老師讓我很開心
I was happy just with that.
只是這樣，我就覺得滿足了
THREE-EIGHT
（三八超商）
"I was so happy
“我很開心
I could be kind to you.
能夠溫柔對待老師
I never imagined
但我從沒想到
it would turn out like this."
事情會變成這樣”
Akira!
阿晶！
How dare you use my Akira as some plaything!
憑什麼利用我家阿晶當妳的玩物？
Don't make Ms. Suenaga quit!
請不要逼老師離職！
That was a mistake!
那樣是不對的
-Get married and go to Osaka. -Ms. Suenaga!
-結婚然後搬去大阪吧 -老師！
I'll never see him again.
我不會再跟他見面了
Subtitle translation by: Zensho Yamamoto
字幕翻譯：楊易